You must be… Roberto.
Kau pasti Roberto.
I have no name.
Aku tak punya nama.
That's unfortunate.
Sayang sekali.
As a police officer,
Sebagai polisi,
I'd at least like to know the name of the murderer who kills me.
aku ingin tahu nama orang yang akan membunuhku.
This is so awful.
Tega sekali.
He was such a nice man too.
Padahal dia begitu baik.
He put his life on the line fighting for us.
Dia mempertaruhkan nyawa untuk melindungi kita.
Mr. Grimmer…
Pak Grimmer.
Dr. Tenma, where are you going?
Dokter Tenma, mau ke mana?
There isn't time for this.
Bukan saatnya di sini.
You're going to Inspector Lunge, aren't you?
Kau mau mencari Inspektur Lunge, 'kan?
I'll go with you. I already have a gun.
Aku ikut. Aku bawa pistol.
A letter…
Surat…
Inspector Lunge gave Mr. Grimmer this letter.
Inspektur Lunge menitip surat ke Grimmer.
He told me that Inspector Lunge found it at the Red Rose Mansion.
Dia bilang Inspektur Lunge menemukannya di Rumah Mawar Merah.
"I've always watched you."
"Aku selalu mengawasimu.
"I've watched you so I could devour all of you."
Aku mengawasimu agar bisa melahapmu.
"But everything about you has devoured me instead."
Tapi sebaliknya, malah kau yang melahapku.
"As I was falling to pieces, how did I appear to you?"
Seperti apa aku yang terpuruk di matamu?
"As I fell to pieces, you gave me something."
Saat aku terpuruk, kau memberikan sesuatu.
"You left me with beautiful gems,
Kau meninggalkan dua permata indah,
those twins who seem to have eternal life."
anak kembar yang seakan-akan hidup abadi.
"The greatest crime is to steal someone's name."
Dosa terbesar adalah merebut nama orang lain.
"Let's get your name back."
Mari ambil kembali namamu.
"I'll give you your name back."
Akan kukembalikan namamu.
"Your name is Anna."
Namamu Anna.
"Now, I am simply sad."
Sekarang aku sedih.
"Sad…
Sedih…
You wrote this, didn't you?
Ini tulisanmu, 'kan?
I fell in love with the mother of those twins.
Aku jatuh cinta kepada ibu kedua anak kembar itu.
My way of thinking changed instantly.
Perspektifku seketika berubah.
That's why I killed everyone who knew about her and the twins
Karena itu orang yang tahu tentang dia, anak kembarnya,
and the experiment.
dan eksperimennya, kuhabisi semuanya.
That's all.
Itu saja.
Tell me, who are you?
Jawab, siapa kau?
If that wound isn't taken care of, you'll die.
Jika lukamu tak dirawat, kau akan mati.
If you want to be saved, answer me.
Jika ingin selamat, jawab aku.
Where is Johan?
Di mana Johan?
Why do you follow Johan so blindly?
Kenapa kau tunduk padanya?
What's your relationship with Johan?
Apa hubunganmu dengan Johan?
You've sure fallen far, Inspector Lunge.
Kau sudah tumpul, Inspektur Lunge.
The most skilled detective of the BKA
Penyidik paling berbakat di BKA
comes to this backwater town alone on vacation without even his badge.
liburan ke kota pinggiran sendirian tanpa membawa lencana.
You dug too deeply into a senate member's scandal
Kau mengorek skandal anggota dewan terlalu dalam
and were deprived of your job,
sampai kasusmu diambil alih.
so chasing after Tenma has become your only reason for living.
Mengejar Tenma jadi satu-satunya alasan hidupmu.
You're exactly right. You've done your homework.
Kau benar. Penyelidikanmu mendetail.
Your wife is living with another man.
Istrimu kini hidup dengan pria lain.
She seems pretty happy.
Dia terlihat bahagia.
Your grandchild even thinks he's her grandfather.
Cucumu pun mengira pria itu kakeknya.
Now that she can speak a little,
Kini cucumu mulai bisa bicara
she calls that man, "Grandpa."
dan memanggil pria itu, "Kakek."
That's enough.
Diam.
I bet you want to see her.
Kau pasti ingin menemuinya.
Your grandchild is quite cute.
Cucumu imut.
I bet you want to see her.
Kau pasti ingin menemuinya.
Silence!
Diam!
You've sure lost your touch.
Kau sudah mulai tumpul.
The old Inspector Lunge wasn't anything like this.
Inspektur Lunge yang dulu tak seperti ini.
Do you want to know who I am?
Kau tahu aku siapa?
Do you want to know my relationship with Johan?
Kau ingin tahu hubunganku dengan Johan?
I have no name. I have no country. I have no memories!
Aku tak punya nama, tanah air, atau ingatan.
The first thing I remember is getting out of that orphanage and getting a job.
Yang kuingat aku keluar panti asuhan dan mendapat pekerjaan.
Then one day, Johan showed up.
Suatu hari, Johan menemuiku.
He reawakened one of my memories.
Dia membangkitkan salah satu ingatanku.
Just one of my memories.
Hanya satu.
What is his real name?
Siapa nama aslinya?
He said he didn't know.
Dia tak tahu.
His name?
Tak tahu namanya sendiri?
Yes.
Ya.
He said he was at an orphanage.
Dia dulu di panti asuhan.
But he told me that even though he forgot everything else,
Tapi katanya, meski hal lainnya lupa,
he remembered his friend's name.
dia ingat nama temannya.
Even though he forgot his own name, he remembered his friend's name?
Dia lupa nama sendiri, tapi dia ingat nama temannya?
Yes. He said his friend liked drawing pictures and liked insects.
Ya. Dia bilang temannya suka menggambar dan suka serangga.
But he hated killing insects,
Tapi dia benci membunuh serangga,
so he would let them out of their insect cages.
jadi dia melepas serangga dari kandangnya.
I think he said the boy's name was… Adolf Reinhart.
Kalau tidak salah, nama temannya Adolf Reinhart.
He said he loved the cocoa they were served once a week.
Katanya dia suka cokelat hangat yang disajikan sepekan sekali.
When Johan noticed me, he gave me a warm mug.
Saat mengenaliku, dia memelukku.
That jogged my memory.
Aku jadi teringat.
The thing I looked forward to once a week at the orphanage…
Satu hal yang kunantikan tiap pekan di panti asuhan…
I loved hot cocoa.
Aku suka cokelat hangat.
If only the rain would wash everything away.
Andai hujan bisa membasuh segalanya.
The fear. The malice. The sadness.
Rasa takut, kebencian, kesedihan.
But it's done the exact opposite.
Tapi efeknya justru sebaliknya.
Everything has grown even more horrible.
Hujan memperparah semuanya.
That day, it rained like this too.
Malam itu, hujannya juga sederas ini.
Mr. Liebert, an East German trade advisor,
Liebert, penasihat Biro Perdagangan Jerman Timur,
who defected a few days ago, has appeared together with his family for the press.
telah tiba mencari suaka. Kemarin beliau menemui pers bersama keluarganya.
Mr. and Mrs. Liebert didn't appear tired,
Bapak dan Ibu Liebert tak tampak lelah.
and the couple along with their two children appeared happy.
Putra dan putri mereka, juga tampak senang.
You've defected as well?
Kau juga mencari suaka?
Yes. From Czechoslovakia.
Ya. Dari Cekoslowakia.
Do you know these children?
Kau kenal anak-anak ini?
Allow me to see them.
Izinkan aku melihat mereka.
Even just for a moment.
Meski cuma sebentar.
Even just to see their sleeping faces.
Atau saat mereka tidur.
That night, tragedy struck.
Malam itu, tragedi terjadi.
There's one survivor, a girl!
Satu orang selamat, anak perempuan!
A man and woman are dead!
Dua orang dewasa tewas.
A boy's in critical condition but has a pulse.
Anak laki-laki dalam kondisi kritis.
-The patient? -BP 72 over 50. Pulse 137.
- Tanda vitalnya? - Tensi 72/50. Denyut nadi 137.
The bullet entered his forehead.
Pelurunya menembus dahinya.
Kill him…
Bunuh…
I didn't know what had happened.
Aku tak tahu yang saat itu terjadi.
No, I was fully aware…
Tidak, aku tahu…
I knew exactly what happened, but I ran away.
Aku tahu yang terjadi, tapi aku kabur.
My brain shut down and I ran away.
Aku berusaha melupakannya dan kabur.
I tried drawing them.
Kucoba menggambar mereka.
Pictures of the perfect twins, those children surrounded by love.
Gambar ideal dua anak kembar yang dikelilingi kasih sayang.
But no matter how many I drew, I couldn't draw them like that.
Tapi meski kucoba berulang kali pun, aku tak bisa menggambarnya.
That's because I understood that it hadn't been that way.
Karena aku paham, kenyataan mereka tak seperti itu.
The Hotel Bergbach
Inspektur Lunge,
where Inspector Lunge is, it's just up ahead?
di Hotel Bergbach dekat sini?
Yes.
Ya.
Let's go.
Ayo.
Be careful. Who knows where they may be.
Hati-hati. Kita bisa diserang dari mana saja.
I…
Aku…
I created a monster.
Aku menciptakan monster.
And I brought that monster back to life.
Dan aku yang membangkitkan monster itu.
You'll never die this way.
Kalau begini, kau tak akan mati.
I've lost the strength in my right arm.
Tangan kananku sudah tak kuat.
You see, Dr. Tenma shot me at that library in Munich.
Gara-gara dr. Tenma menembakku di perpustakaan kota München.
It would have been easy to have killed him there.
Sebenarnya mudah membunuhnya di sana.
But I wasn't supposed to.
Tapi aku tak boleh membunuhnya.
Dr. Tenma is the person who must remain.
Dokter Tenma harus tetap hidup.
He'll live to the end and be all alone.
Dia harus hidup dan sendirian.
He will die lonely and sad and without a name.
Dia akan mati kesepian, bersedih, dan tanpa nama.
That is all part of Johan's calculations.
Semua sudah diperhitungkan Johan.
Dr. Tenma has been allowed to see the scenery that Johan has seen.
Dokter Tenma diizinkan melihat pemandangan yang dilihat Johan.
I want to see that scenery as well.
Aku juga ingin melihat pemandangannya.
I want to see it.
Aku ingin melihatnya.
Inspector Lunge, you will not see it!
Inspektur Lunge, kau tak akan melihatnya!
You will die!
Kau akan mati!
This too…
Ini juga…
is part of Johan's calculations.
sudah diperhitungkan Johan.
Calculations, you say?
Perhitungan, katamu?
On the computer in my mind, those calculations don't add up!
Di komputer dalam otakku, perhitungan itu tak masuk akal!
Answer me! Where is Johan?
Jawab! Di mana Johan?
This is awful. It's like a battlefield.
Mengerikan. Seperti medan perang.
Johan is not here.
Johan tak di sini.
How can you tell?
Tahu dari mana?
He's watching what happens here from somewhere.
Dia mengawasi semuanya dari suatu tempat.
Like watching a line of ants.
Seperti melihat barisan semut.
Anyway, let's check things out inside.
Sementara, mari cek ke dalam.
Tenma was headed here.
Karena Tenma sempat kemari.
Anyone here? Anyone?
Ada orang? Ada orang di sini?
I'll check the second floor.
Aku akan cek lantai dua.
A child…
Anak kecil…
Stay back!
Jangan mendekat!
It's all right. We're on your side. We're here to help you.
Tak apa. Kami di pihakmu. Kami ingin menolongmu.
See? We're not carrying anything.
Lihat, kami tak membawa pistol.
Right? It's okay, see?
Ya? Tak apa, 'kan?
The woman from the pictures.
Perempuan di gambar.
From what pictures?
Apa maksudmu?
There were a bunch of drawings. You look just like the girl in them.
Ada banyak gambar. Kau mirip perempuan di gambar itu.
A bunch of drawings?
Banyak gambar?
They were drawings of twins, and the boy looked just like her.
Gambar anak kembar, dan laki-lakinya mirip dia.
Where did you see those pictures?
Di mana gambar-gambar itu?
Where did you see them?
Di mana?
In the hills to the south…
Di bukit daerah selatan,
at the vampire's house.
di rumah vampir.
Doesn't anyone know?
Apa tak ada yang tahu?
Do you know where my son is? Do you?
Kau tak tahu anakku di mana? Hei.
Where did Wim go?
Wim ke mana?
They're… all dead…
Semuanya tewas…
A devil…
Iblis…
A devil has come to this town!
Iblis datang ke kota ini!
It doesn't look like there's anyone here.
Sepertinya tak ada orang di rumah ini.
Not long ago, Johan was right there just like you are now.
Belum lama ini, Johan juga berdiri di sini sepertimu.
Isn't that right?
Benar, 'kan?
They're all drawings someone tried to make of you
Sepertinya orang ini berusaha menggambar kalian,
but was unable to finish.
tapi tak bisa rampung.
In all the drawings, you're smiling gently.
Di semua gambar ini, kalian tersenyum.
But the one who drew them was Franz Bonaparta.
Tapi yang menggambar semua ini adalah Franz Bonaparta.
What did Johan think when he was looking at them?
Apa yang Johan pikirkan saat melihatnya?
Welcome back.
Selamat datang.
I'm back.
Aku pulang.
Nina.
Nina.
I… saw something frightening.
Aku melihat hal yang mengerikan.
It was very… very frightening.
Teramat sangat menakutkan.
There were lots of dead people.
Banyak sekali korban jiwa.
At the Red Rose Mansion,
Di Rumah Mawar Merah,
everyone drank wine…
semua minum anggur…
Then…
Kemudian,
they were all choking and falling in a heap right in front of me!
mereka semua tersedak dan berjatuhan di hadapanku!
Where is Mother?
Ibu di mana?
I'm sorry.
Maaf.
Why are you apologizing?
Kenapa kau minta maaf?
At that time…
Saat itu…
the two of you… had to live…
kalian berdua harus hidup…
You two had to live…
Kalian berdua harus hidup…
Why are you crying?
Kenapa kau menangis?
Don't cry!
Jangan menangis!
Don't cry…
Jangan menangis.
Nina!
Nina!
He… was crying…
Dia menangis.
Nina.
Nina.
In this room…
Di ruangan ini…
Not long ago in this very room,
Belum lama, di ruangan ini,
he was here alone.
dia sendirian.
He was crying like that one time.
Dia pernah menangis seperti itu.
On that rainy night…
Di malam yang hujan itu,
if I hadn't shot him…
andai aku tak menembaknya…
If only I had forgiven him, this wouldn't have continued.
Andai aku memaafkannya, semua ini takkan berlanjut.
All these people wouldn't have died.
Orang-orang ini tak harus mati.
It's probably too late now.
Mungkin sudah terlambat.
But now's the time.
Tapi ini saatnya.
Where is Johan now?
Johan di mana?
He's gone into the town.
Dia pergi ke kota.
He's going there to end it all.
Untuk mengakhiri segalanya.